ILGWU. Susan Cowell papers, 5780/097
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Susan Cowell papers
1923-2002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Cowell, Susan.
5780/097
26 cubic feet
25.5 linear feet
Records
Correspondence, speeches, and books of Susan Cowell, Vice President of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
6766598
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
June 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
In 1981, Susan Cowell began working with the ILGWU as a staff member in the Department of Organization and Field Services, designing and conducting surveys and questionnaires and organizing Korean garment workers. In September 1982, she became Assistant to the Manager of Local 23-25 Jay Mazur, and beginning in 1983, when Mazur became General Secretary-Treasurer, Cowell served as Assistant to the General Secretary-Treasurer. In 1986, Cowell was Executive Assistant to the President of the ILGWU, and the next year, she was elected Vice President of the union, a position she held until the merger of the ILGWU with ACTWU to form UNITE in 1995. Prior to working for the ILGWU, Cowell worked as consultant, free-lance writer and editor, and teacher. She holds degrees from Brown University, Harvard University, and Yale University.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, speeches, and books of Susan Cowell, Vice President of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
6000/023. UNITE. Susan Cowell. Vice President files
General
"Permanent deposit"
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Cowell, Susan.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees
6766598
- ILGWU Member Survey, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ILGWU Business Development Proposed Contracts, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ILGWU Fashion Show, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ILGWU Fashion Show Public Relations, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- IGLWU Fashion Show: Schools, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Solidarity Day Materials [folder 1 of 2], 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Solidarity Day Materials [folder 2 of 2], 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "NY is Fashion" Budget, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Advertisements, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Daily News Strike, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Daily News Advertisements, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Daily News Press, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Election Activities, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Garment Center Rally, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Primary Elections, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Presidential Poll, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Mammography Project, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Hospitals, Re: Mammography, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- UHC Survey Results (Box 1, Folder 19)
- UHC 7th Anniversary, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Clippings, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Democratic Convention, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Voter Registration and Turnout, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Presidential Election, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Kitty Dukakis Garment Center Visit, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Dukakis Literature (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Dukakis Literature and Letters (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Dinkins. Retiree Activities, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Dinkins. General, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Dinkins. ILGWU Campaign, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- New York City Elections, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- UHC Book, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Dinkins Press Conference, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Voter Registration Radio, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dinkins Survey, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Resolutions Committee, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Jay Mazur. Acceptance Speech, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 1986 Convention, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Transition to President, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Jay Mazur. Election Publicity, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Resolutions Committee, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 1983 Convention. Press Releases (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Resolutions Committee, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Convention Resolutions. Locals 23-25, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Jay Mazur. Congratulations Responses (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Convention Proceedings, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Giveaways and Sale Items, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Video at Convention, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Travel and Logistics, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- General Executive Board Book, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- 1986 Convention Planning (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Convention Hall Decorations, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Exhibits, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Workshops, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Publications, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Social Events, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Retiree Activity, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Public Relations, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Dues, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Childcare, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Handbook of Architectural Design Competitions, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Mierle Laderman Ukeles. Final Project, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- City Arts Background, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Sculpture Background, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- AFL-CIO Asian Committee, APALA, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Sculpture Finalists, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Sculpture Project, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Statue of Liberty. Press, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Statue of Liberty. Frontlash Essay Contest, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Statue of Liberty. Centennial Commission, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Statue of Liberty. AFL-CIO Convention, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Statue of Liberty. ILGWU, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Statue of Liberty Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- ILGWU Statue of Liberty Fundraising, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Statue of Liberty. Passover Seder, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Statue of Liberty. Latin Dance, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Statue of Liberty. Italian Street Fair, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Statue of Liberty. Boat Ride, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Local 23-25. Korean Program, 1981-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  English and Korean
- Local 23-25. Korean Language (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Chicago Koreans, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Korean Immigrants (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Chinatown Chinese Community, 1984-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Chinese Press on Local 23-25, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Asian American Workers. Miscellaneous, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Greater Blouse Association, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Greater Blouse Association, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Chinatown Press Summaries, 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Asian Workers Sensitivity Training, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Chinese-Americans, 1983-1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Vincent Chin, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Hong Kong (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Chinese Language, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Chinese and English
- Local 23-25 Contracts, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Spanish and English
- Contract Enforcement, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- ILGWU Health and Welfare Funds. Off the Books, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Posters. "We Are One", 1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Mazur, Jay. Speeches, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Organizing Segment, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- ILG Chorus, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- ILG Chorus. Music and History, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Convention Speakers, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Imports Committee, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- ILGWU Convention Program, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- ILGWU Convention Videos, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- ILGWU Convention Committee Materials, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Convention Resolutions, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Convention Follow-Up, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Letters to Affiliates, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Convention Follow-Up, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Mazur, Jay. Speeches, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 1992 Convention Preparations, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Convention Program and Speeches, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Convention Floor plans, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Associate ILGWU Member Meeting, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Rank and File Awards, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Workshops, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- 1992 Conference Video (Box 3, Folder 16)
- CWA and AT&T, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Retiree Service Department. Silver Needle Awards Luncheon, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- International Relations Committee, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Child Care Services, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Convention Committees and Resolutions, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Convention Public Relations and Press, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Printing and Graphics, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- ILG Chorus, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- The Struggle of 1982. Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Three-Year Report, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Consulting Organizing Group Articles (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Chinatown Rally. English Press Coverage, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Local 23-25 Membership Statistics Survey (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Media Survey Results (Box 4, Folder 25)
- R.S. Clough and Associates, Inc. Reports and Correspondences, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Leader Data Processing Computers, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Word Processing Materials, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Data Processing Committee, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Northeast Surveys (Box 4, Folder 30)
- General Polling, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Philips Center. General, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Phone Banks (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Videos. Miscellaneous, 1983-1993 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Global Assembly Line, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Publications and Subscriptions, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Publicity (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Organizing Leaflets (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Organizing Manuals (Box 4, Folder 39)
- SEIU Strike Manual (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Grand Street Coops and East River Housing, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- IGLWU Housing, 1988-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Housing. Miscellaneous, 1984-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Chung Pak, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Other Union Housing, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- United Housing Foundation, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Settlement Housing Fund, 1982-1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Triangle Fire Commemoration, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Fire Safety and Triangle Fire Commemoration, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Triangle Fire Commemoration and OSHA Reform, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Triangle Fire Commemoration, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Triangle Fire Commemoration, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Triangle Fire. Miscellaneous, 1983-1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Triangle Fire. 75th Anniversary, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Triangle Fire. Commemoration, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Triangle Fire. Commemoration, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Triangle Fire. Commemoration, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Pins and Needles. Miscellaneous, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Unity House. Miscellaneous, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- ILG Archives, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Rudy Lozano, 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- ILG History, 1985-1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Smithsonian Museum. Correspondences., 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Histadrut. Speeches, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Mazur, Jay. ILG Speeches, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Mazur, Jay. Speeches, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Mazur, Jay. Speeches, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Mazur, Jay. Speeches, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Mazur, Jay. Speeches, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Mazur, Jay. Speeches, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Brooklyn Army Terminal Project, ACTWU, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Barneys New York. Correspondences, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Out-of-Business ILGWU Stores, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Lerner Stores. Articles, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Honey Fashions, Ltd. Elowitz, Norman. Correspondences, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Capraro, Albert. Articles, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Ju-El Manufacturing. Correspondences, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Just Plastics, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Liz Claiborne. Articles., 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Poirette Corset, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Tony Scuito Correspondences, Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Apparel Trimming, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Donenfeld Knitwear, Inc., 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Harmal, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- American Jewish Congress. New York Metropolitan Council, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Commission of the Year 2000, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- New York Interface Development Project, Inc., 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- New York State Economic Development, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Regional Plan Association, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- New York City Economic Development, 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Rebuild New York Coalition, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Lazes, Peter. Programs for Employment and Workplace Systems, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Hatch, Richard. Italian Industrialism, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- ILGWU Labor Management Committees, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Trade Adjustment Assistance Center, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Fashion Institute of Technology, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- ICC State Project, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Chicago, Miscellaneous, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Philadelphia, Miscellaneous, 1983-1988 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Fall River, Massachusetts, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Pennsylvania, Miscellaneous, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Boston, Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Wiener Study. Zoning Measures, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Zoning for Hotels, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Loft Tenants in M-Zones, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Loft Board, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Brooklyn Zoning, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Industry Desks, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Business Relocation Assistance Corporation, 1984-1988 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- City Programs for Industry, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Industrial Retention and Relocation Program, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Massachusetts High-Tech, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Miscellaneous Zoning Issues, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Zoning Commercial Conversions, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Intra Manhattan Relocation, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Industrial Relocation Grants. Survey, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- West Side Production Center, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Training Programs, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Government Contracts, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Industrial Loft Advisory Committee, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- City Planning Chinatown Study, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- New York City Real Estate Articles, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Walker Street Corridor Issues, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Second Chinatown Garment Industry Zoning Change, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Special Manhattan Bridge District. Henry Street, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  English and Chinese
- Soho and Noho Districts. General, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation Formation, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Legal Documents, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Budgets and Financial Statements, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Annual Report, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Expansion, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Press, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  Chinese
- Meeting with Mayor Koch, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  March 23, 1988
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Real Estate, 1984-1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Meeting with Banks, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- P.S.20 Conversion Project, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. 424 Broadway Project, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Real Estate Data, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Outer-Borough Garment Industry Study, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation. Training Program, 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- ILG Comments and Draft Environmental Impact Statement, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- 42nd Street Project. ILG General Statements, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- 42nd Street Project, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- 42nd Street Project. Press Coverage, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Garment Center Study. Roger Waldinger, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- CPC/OED Study of the Garment Center, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Garment Center Census, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Harris Survey and Questionnaires, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Garment Center. Policy Recommendations, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Garment Center. Press Coverage, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Garment Center. Implementation, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Garment Center. ILG Testimony, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Garment Center. City Planning Meetings, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Garment Center. Board of Hearing Estimate, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Garment Center. Enforcement Project, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Garment Center. Zoning Suit, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Letter on 42nd Street. Garment Industry Advisory Committee, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Con Edison Rates, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- New York State Programs, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Submetering, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Imports, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Garment Industry Advisory Committee, 1983-1991 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Chinatown Study. Press Materials and Drafts, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Chinatown Study. Press Conference, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Chinatown Study. Press Conference, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Chinatown Study. Press Coverage, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Article for Empire State Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Chinatown Study Follow-Up, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Excerpts from Environmental Impact Statement Draft (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Environment Impact Statement Draft. Comments, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Final Environmental Impact Statement. Excerpts, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- New York State Urban Development Corporation. 42nd Street Project Hearing, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- New York State Urban Development Corporation. ILG Comments, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- New York State Urban Development Corporation. Hearing Follow-Up, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Garment Center. Mayor Statement, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Rent Control. Press Coverage, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Small Business Rent Control, 1983-1988 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Mayor's Commission and Statement, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Commercial Rent Control Hearings, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Commercial Rent Control Hearings, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Commercial Rent Control Hearings, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Garment Industry Task Force, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- ACTWU and Manufacturing Coalition, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Placement of Manufacturing. Background and Press, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Commercial Conversions, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Manhattan Real Estate, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Development Manufacturing Space, 1985-1989 (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Local 10 Displaced Shops, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 55)
- City Council Hearings, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Assemblyman Jerrold Nadler, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 57)
- New York Garment Industry Task Force Papers, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Rainfair. Correspondences, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Rainfair Press [folder 1 of 2], 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Rainfair Press [folder 2 of 2], 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Boycott Rainfair Materials (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Rainfair Boycott [folder 1 of 2], 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Rainfair Boycott [folder 2 of 2], 1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- EPC Panel. Jay Mazur Speech, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Economic Policy Council. Newly Emerging Industrial Countries, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Economics, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Part-Time and Temporary Work, 1986-1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Unemployment, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Inequality. 2-Tiered Economy, 1986-1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Blacks and the Economy, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Labor Statistics (Box 8, Folder 14)
- The Magazine Retort, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Industrial Policy, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Industrial Union Department. Industry Policy, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Worker Ownership, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- World of Work. Work in America, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Council on Economic Priorities, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Tyler, Gus. Miscellaneous, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 21)